Guide to the Michael Arad 9/11 Memorial Papers 2001-2019 PR 422
New-York Historical Society
Michael Arad 9/11 Memorial papers
2001-2019
New-York Historical Society
Arad, Michael, 1969-
PR 422
78.85 Linear feet in 62 boxes, 3 bins and 12 folders
122 Gigabytes consisting of 26,995 digital files in 2,440 folders
This collection contains material from the records of the architect Michael Arad (1969- ), primarily related to his design of the National September 11 Memorial in New York City, which opened to the public on September 11, 2011.
Content Description
This collection contains material from the records of the architect Michael Arad (1969- ), primarily related to his design of the National September 11 Memorial in New York City. Arad's design for the 9/11 Memorial at the World Trade Center site is titled "Reflecting Absence," and was selected by the Lower Manhattan Development Corporation from among more than 5,000 entries submitted in an international competition in 2003. The collection includes architectural drawings, photographs and prints, office files, correspondence, proposals, presentations, memorabilia, models, digital files, and other media that document the design and construction of the memorial, which opened to the public on September 11, 2011.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 8 series:
Series I: Architectural Drawings
Series II: Digital Material
Series III: Ephemera and Other Media
Series IV: Images - Photographs and Prints
Series V: Names Parapet
Series VI: Office Files
Series VII: Site Models and Objects
Series VIII: Other Projects (not WTC)
Biographical / Historical
Michael Arad (1969- ) is an Israeli-American architect who designed the National September 11 Memorial in New York City. Arad, an Israeli citizen, was born in London, where his father Moshe Arad worked as a press attache. Arad later lived in New York City, Washington D.C., Jerusalem, and Mexico City. He also served for three years in the Israel Defense Forces.
Arad received a bachelor's degree from Dartmouth College, and a master's degree from Georgia Institute of Technology's College of Architecture. He moved to New York City in 1999 and practiced architecture at the firm of Kohn Pedersen Fox for three years. At the time he submitted his design to the competition for the World Trade Center site memorial, Arad was working for the New York City Housing Authority, designing neighborhood police stations.
Michael Arad's design for the 9/11 Memorial at the World Trade Center site, titled "Reflecting Absence," was selected by the Lower Manhattan Development Corporation from among more than 5,000 entries submitted in an international competition held in 2003. In April 2004, Arad joined the New York firm of Handel Architects; at this time, the LMDC also chose landscape architect Peter Walker, and the firm of Davis Brody Bond LLP to work with Arad in the realization of the design for the memorial.
The 9/11 Memorial was conceived and designed as a tribute to the 2,977 people killed in the terror attacks of September 11, 2001 at the World Trade Center, at the crash site near Shanksville, Pennsylvania, and at the Pentagon, as well as the six people killed in the World Trade Center bombing on February 26, 1993. Arad's design, "Reflecting Absence," features twin waterfall pools situated in the footprints of the original Twin Towers. The pools are each surrounded by bronze parapets that list the names of the victims of the 9/11 attacks and the 1993 World Trade Center bombing. They are set within a plaza planted with more than 400 swamp white oak trees. The National 9/11 Memorial opened on September 11, 2011. In 2012, Arad was awarded the AIA Presidential Citation for his work on the National September 11 Memorial.
N.B. When the project was originally conceived by the Lower Manhattan Development Corporation, it was called the World Trade Center Site Memorial. Currently, the formal name is the National September 11th Memorial, and it is informally known as the 9/11 Memorial. Alternately, it is sometimes referred to as the World Trade Center Memorial, the Ground Zero Memorial, or the Twin Towers Memorial.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact the Print Room Reference Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Some formats, such as CDs, DVDs, VHS tapes and certain digital files, may not be accessible due to file corruption or because the library does not have the equipment or proprietary software necessary to make the information they contain accessible. While some media may no longer be used as originally intended, they may be of interest as archival objects.
Models are restricted due to their fragility. Special permission to view the models must be received from both the curator and the chief conservator. All requests must be made in advance and in writing.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Michael Arad, 2020
Architects -- New York (State) -- New York.; Architectural records.; Files (digital files); Memorials -- New York (State) -- New York.; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001.; World Trade Center Site (New York, N.Y.); Lower Manhattan Development Corporation; National September 11 Memorial & Museum (Organization)
- Series I: Architectural Drawings, 2003-2017
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains architectural sketches and drawing sets, many of which are annotated. They are arranged by title or subject, and listed chronologically.
  - Subseries I.A: Bid Drawing Sets, 2007-2009
    - Drawings Issued for Bid, volumes 1 and 2, 2007 June 1 (Offsite-box 24)
    - Plaza Stone Package for Bid, 2009 August 19 (Offsite-box 25)
  - Subseries I.B: Design Development Sets, 2005-2007
    - 50% Design Development Progress Set, 2004 December 15 (Offsite-box 16)
    - 50% Design Development Progress Set, 2005 March 1 (Offsite-box 16)
    - Design Development Progress Set, 2005 July 15 (Offsite-box 13)
    - Design Development, Handel Record Set, volumes 1-4, 2005 September 14 (Offsite-box 14)
    - Design Development, Check Set, volumes 1-4, 2005 September 14 (Offsite-box 15)
    - 25% Design Development Progress Report, volumes 1 and 2, 2006 January 31 (Offsite-box 17)
    - Design Development Progress Set, Construction Documents, volumes 1 and 2, 2006 April 17 (Offsite-box 18)
    - Design Development Progress Set, Construction Documents, volumes 3 and 4, 2006 April 17 (Offsite-box 19)
    - Design Development Progress Set, Construction Documents, volumes 1, 3 and 4, 2006 April 17 (Offsite-box 20)
    - Design Development Progress Set, 25% Construction Documents, volumes 1, 2 and 4, 2006 August 17 (Offsite-box 21)
    - Design Development Progress Set, 25% Construction Documents, volume 3, 2006 (Offsite-box 53)
    - Design Development Progress Prints, volumes 1, 3 and 4, 2007 February 19 (Offsite-box 22)
    - Design Development Progress Prints, volume 3, 2007 (Offsite-box 53)
    - Design Development Progress Set, volumes 1 and 2, 2007 March 1 (Offsite-box 23)
  - Subseries I.C: Design Principals Presentation Sets, 8.5 x 11 inches, 2004-2005
    - Preliminary Design Coordination Drawings, 8.5 x 11 inches, 2004 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
    - Design Principals Presentations, 8.5 x 11 inches, Mar-May 2005 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
    - Design Principals Presentations, 8.5 x 11 inches, Jun 2005 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 17)
    - Design Principals Presentations, 8.5 x 11 inches, Jul 2005 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 18)
    - Design Principals Presentations, 8.5 x 11 inches, Aug 2005 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Design Principals Presentations, 8.5 x 11 inches, 2005 September-October (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3)
    - Design Principals Presentations, 8.5 x 11 inches, 2005 November-December (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4)
    - Design Principals Presentations, 8.5 x 11 inches, 2005 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 1-6)
  - Subseries I.D: Design Principals Meeting and Presentation Sets, 11 x 17 inches, 2005
    - Design Principals Meeting, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 February 10 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
    - Design Principals Meeting, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 February 23 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
    - Design Principals Presentation, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 March 10 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
    - Design Principals Presentation, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 March 31 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
    - Design Principals Presentation, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 April 20 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5)
    - Design Principals Presentation, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 May 12 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 6)
    - Design Principals Presentation, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 June 3 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 7)
    - Design Principals Presentation, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 June 22 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 8)
    - Design Principals Presentation, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 June 23 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
    - Design Principals Meeting, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 July 14 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - Design Principals Meeting, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 Aug 4 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 3)
    - Design Principals Meeting, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 Aug 25 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 4)
    - Design Principals Meeting, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 September 13 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 5)
    - Design Principals Meeting, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 October 6 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
    - Design Principals Meeting, 11x17 inches, 2005 October 28 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
    - Design Principals Meeting, 11x17 inches, 2005 December 8 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
    - Design Principals Meeting, 11 x 17 inches, 2005 (Offsite-box 47)
  - Subseries I.E: Handel Record Sets, 2004-2007
    - Handel Record Set, 2004 July 21 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4)
    - Handel Record Set, 2004 September 24 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 5)
    - Handel Record Set, 2004 November 5 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
    - Handel Record Set, 2005 January 6 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
    - Handel Record Set, 2005 February 10 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
    - Handel Record Set, 2005 March 31 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8)
    - Handel Record Set, 2005 April 21 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1)
    - Handel Record Set, 2004-2007 (Offsite-box 54)
  - Subseries I.F: Museum and Gallery Drawings Sets, 2005-2009
    - Circulation Diagram Memorial Access Option 1, 2004 July 30 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 3)
    - Gallery and Contemplation Room Study, 2004 July 21 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 3)
    - Memorial Gallery Scheme Comparison, 2005 June 17 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 5)
    - Memorial Gallery Scheme Comparison, 2005 (Offsite-box 49)
    - Memorial Hall and Viewing Gallery, 2005 (Offsite-box 31, Box 4)
    - Memorial Hall and Viewing Gallery, 2005-2006 (Offsite-box 49)
    - Museum Exhibition Schematic Design, 2008 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 6)
  - Subseries I.G: Schematic Design Sets, 2004
    - Schematic Design Progress Set, Schemes A and B, 2004 November 15 (Offsite-box 25)
    - Schematic Designs, 2004 December 15 (Offsite-box 16)
    - Schematic Design, 2004 (Offsite-box 46)
  - Subseries I.H: Sketches, undated
    - Book of Sketches, printed and bound, undated (Offsite-box 33, Folder 1)
    - Sketches on Trace Paper, undated (Offsite-box 34, Folder 1-5)
    - Sketches on Trace Paper, undated (Offsite-box 50)
    - Sketches on Trace, 2001-2003, undated (Folder FF1)
      Five oversize sketches, four small sketches.
  - Subseries I.J: Drawing Sets, Other, 2003-2017
    - Access Drawings, 2004 July 21 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
    - Access Drawings, 2004 (Offsite-box 46)
    - Access to Bedrock Studies Option 1 at Memorial Level, 2004 July 29 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
    - Advanced Footings and Foundation Set, 2006 January 17 (Offsite-box 17)
    - Bedrock Level Plans, 2004 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 7)
    - Circulation Diagram, 2004 August 11 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
    - Design / Experience Issues, 2006 February 21 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
    - Design Intent and Design Issues, 2004-2006 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Fountains and Pools, 2005-2010 (Offsite-box 47)
    - Grading Diagram, 2004 August 11 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
    - Liberty Street Facade Refinement, 2013 February (Offsite-box 31, Folder 2)
    - LMDC Drawing Sets, 2003-2007 (Offsite-box 48)
    - Materials, 2006 (Offsite-box 46)
    - Memorial Access Options, 2004 August 11 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
    - Memorial Lighting, 2009 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Wayfinding, 2006 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 7)
    - Memorial Plaza- Night Lighting, 2005 May 12 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Plaza Studies, 2009 March (Offsite-box 31, Folder 1)
    - Memorial Plaza Integration of Commemorative Element, 2017 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 4)
    - North East Corner Study, 2006-2007 (Offsite-box 48)
    - North East Corner Study, 2007 June (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7)
    - PATH Station Skylights, 2005 May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
    - Plan 1 - Plan 5 and Section Pool Edge Options 1-5, 2004 September 9 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
    - Port Authority Drawings, 2006 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
    - Ramp Studies, 2004 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
    - Ramp Studies, 2005 March 2 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
    - Ramp Studies, 2005 April (Offsite-box 44, Folder 7)
    - Ramp Studies, 2004-2006 (Offsite-box 48)
    - Security Options and Reviews, 2006 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
    - Security Options and Reviews, 2006 (Offsite-box 46)
    - Shop Drawings, 2010 (Offsite-box 48)
    - Staging Plans, 2004-2006 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
    - Studies A.1 - F.5, 2005 January 27 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
    - Superstructure Steel Set, 2007 February 19 (Offsite-box 23)
    - Survivor Tree Options, 2012 March (Offsite-box 31, Folder 2)
    - Value Engineering Options, 2006 June (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
    - Value Engineering Options, 2006 (Offsite-box 46)
    - Vertical Access Scheme, 2004 August 11 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
    - Vertical Access Scheme, 2004 (Offsite-box 46)
    - World Trade Center Footprint Studies, 2005 (Offsite-box 46)
    - World Trade Center Masterplan- Structural Concept, 2003 October (Offsite-box 11, Folder 2)
    - World Trade Center District Overall Concept Plan, 2008 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
  - Subseries I.K: Oversize Drawings, 2004-2009
    - Consultant Set, 2004 (Offsite-box 59)
    - Consultant Set, 2004 (Offsite-box 60)
    - Consultant Set, 2004 (Offsite-box 61)
    - Consultant Set, 2004 (Offsite-box 62)
    - Geometry Plans, 2004-2007 (Folder FF6)
    - Plans, Access, Sections, 2004 (Folder FF9)
    - Port Authority Drawings, 2007 (Folder FF7)
    - Port Morris Tile and Marble Company Drawings, 2009 (Folder FF8)
    - Preliminary Design Coordination Drawings, 2004 (Folder FF13)
    - Supplemental Materials and Layout Plans, 2009 (Folder FF10)
    - Traffic Flow, World Trade Center site, 2003 (Folder FF4)
    - Vertical Access Schemes, 2004 (Folder FF5)
    - Oversize Folded Drawings, 2009-2010 (Offsite-box 51)
- Series II: Digital Material, 2003-2011; 122 Gigabytes (26,995 files)
  This series consists of CDs and DVDs and the digital files that were extracted from them. The CDs and DVDs did not arrive in any discernible order; the Digital Archivist numbered each CD and DVD, and transcribed any titles or information found on them. Each of the entries in this Subseries II.A represents one CD/DVD, and contains many individual files. Some of these files may not be accessible due to file corruption or because the library does not have the equipment or proprietary software necessary to make the information they contain accessible. The container list below includes the titles of the first level of folder organization within that digital content. Date ranges are provided, but are all approximate. A full manifest of the individual files comprising the series is available from the reference librarian on request.
  - Subseries II.A: Digital Files, 2003-2011
    These digital files were extracted from the CDs and DVDs that are part of this series. The CDs and DVDs did not arrive in any discernible order; the Digital Archivist numbered each CD and DVD, and transcribed any titles or information found on them. Each of the entries in this series represents one CD/DVD, and contains many individual files. Some of these files may not be accessible due to file corruption or because the library does not have the proprietary software necessary. The container list below includes the titles of the first level of folder organization within that digital content. Date ranges are provided, but are all approximate. A full manifest of the individual files comprising the series is available from the reference librarian on request.
    - 1_7_10_Slides for PPT, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 2_JuryBoards, 2003 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 3_Images for Powerpoint, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 4_Michael_Backup_Feb_12_04_1, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 5_Michael_Backup_Feb_12_04_2, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 6_IMG_28_30_CompetitionBoards, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 7_IMG_1_27_MichaelVariousScans_Feb04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 8_Michael_Various_Jan_22_04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 9_Michael_VariousFileImagesEtc_Early, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 10_Press Images_03_08_04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 11_Powerpoint_March04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 12_DVD_2_2, 2003 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 13_Animation_MArad, 2003 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 16_ImagesFromPWP_April04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 17_WTCMasterplanDiagrams_1-26-04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 18_AVIFilesDesignIntentCurrent, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 19_Powerpoint_April04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 20_OfficeofEmergencyManagementPPT, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 21_March26Set_EnvDefPackage, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 22_PA-KPFComplianceStandards_03-10-04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 23_ToJBBPANYNJ_March0204, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 24_July21LayoutsforDPMeeting, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 25_SacredSpacePrecedent_MarkPasnik, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 26_RandomDocuments_Oct-Jan2005_DBB (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 27_Pentagon_Memorial, 2003 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 28_SchematicDesignSet_12-15-04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 29_WTC_MP_Reconciliation, 2003 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 30_WTC_CurrentTransferToDBB_10-18-04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 31_WTC_BackupMoveToDBB_Oct-18-04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 32_WTC_BackupMoveToDBB_Oct-18-04_2, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 33_WTC_DirectoryAtKPFTransfer, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 34_WTC_DirectoryAtKPFImages, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 35_WTC_DirectoryAtKPFLibrary, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 36_WTC_DirectoryAtKPFDocumentsDrawings, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 38_SiteSlurryWall_1-27-04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 39_WestStSlurryWallEtc_03-23-04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 41_Handel_PA_Conflicts_09-04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 42_Route9AAlternatives_Vollmer_02-06-04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 43_Michael_Images_Mar04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 44_Michael_VariousImages_Mar04, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 45_PowerpointPresentation_DartmouthConvocation, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 46_SchemeA_Archive_4LScheme_Nov2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 47_WTC_SchematicDesignSet_Dec2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 48_DPPresentations_Jan-Mar2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 49_HandelMoveBack050127_1, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 50_HandelMoveBack050127_2, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 51_Finalists_LMDC_Competition, 2003 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 52_DBoxAnimationOfSchematics, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 53_911_Memorial, 2011 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 54_Arad_09-14-2011 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 55_HandelArchitects_National911Memorial_1, 2011 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 56_HandelArchitects_National911Memorial_2, 2011 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 57_Michael Arad_I_National911Memorial, 2011 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 58_June2011_National911MemorialPresentation (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 59_TheMarker, 2008 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 60_[no_label], 2007 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 61_RAMFS_Presentation, 2004 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 62_050720_LMDC_BoardMTG_Ramp_Slot, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 63_MemorialAnimations_SchemeAandB, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 64_911Memories_MahaProductions, 2011 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 65_DowntownAlliance_Arad2008 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 66_[crossed_out]_DowntownAlliance_03, 2008 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 67_Klausmeier_050708 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 68_WTC_Mem_PoolWindowTest_09May07, 2007 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 69_Hub_Mezzanine_Files_06-07 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 70_PSA_Views_DBOX_August2003 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 71_Pataki_06-02-01_WTC_Memorial_Arad, 2006 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 72_ConventionPPTRevised, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 73_MemorialAnimations_SchemeA_HallB, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 74_WTCMemorial_Fountain_Mockup_Sept, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 75_WTCM_Archive_050708, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 76_WTCM_KPF_Archive_Disc1and2, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 77_MemorialAnimations_SchemeAandB, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 78_MemorialAnimationsTest_02-20-05 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 79_MemorialAnimations_2-3-05, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 80_[no_label], 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 81_Descent_to_Bedrock_Animations_3-10-05, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 82_MemorialAnimations_1-27-05, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 83_DDP-PA1081-07_WTC_Transportation, 2006-2007 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 84_FirefighterMemorial_6-13-06, 2006 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 85_Backgrounds_060609_Snohetta, 2006 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 86_PATH_Mezzanine_BelowGrade_Sketch, 2006 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 87_WorldTradeCenterMasterPlan_Drawings, 2003 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 88_PressKit_911Memorial, 2011 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 89_WTC_TIFF_Final_6-28-03, 2003 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 90_DP_Meetings, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 91_ForMichaelArad_AmyDrener, 2010-2011 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 92_Proj_Admin_Post, 2003 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 93_MockUpPhotos, 2006 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 94_WTC_IFC_DCSchematicDesign_August, 2005 (Digital-folder PR 422)
    - 95_12-14-05_ComputerCCEgressAnalysis (Digital-folder PR 422)
  - Subseries II.B: CDs and DVDs, 2003-2011
    This subseries contains 95 CDs and DVDs. The contents of these discs has been copied, and is listed in Subseries II.A: Digital Files. Some of the discs were inaccessible due to file corruption; these have been labeled "discard." Access to the contents of any of the CDs and DVDs is exclusively through the Digital Files. However, the discs may be of interest as archival objects.
    - CDs and DVDs, 2003-2011 (Offsite-box 35)
- Series III: Ephemera and Other Media, 2001-2019
  This series consists of items related to Michael Arad and the 9/11 Memorial, including ID badges, magazine and newspaper articles, informational cards, posters, sheet music, and stickers. It also includes media such as VHS tapes, which are restricted from access because of fragility of the media and the library does not have the necessary equipment.
  - Badges, identification and Security, 2004-2014 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 1)
  - Guides to Lower Manhattan, 2002-2005 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 10)
  - Guide, Board of Directors Site Tour, 2009 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 2)
  - Informational Cards from Memorial Groundbreaking, 2006 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 3)
  - Informational Cards, Lower Manhattan Lecture Series, 2008 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 4)